http://www.huddersfieldchoral.com/privacy-policy/

1. INTRODUCTION
The HCS is committed to protecting your privacy and security. This policy explains how and why we use your personal data, to ensure you remain informed and in control of your information.
From March 2018, HCS will ask its supporters to “opt-in” for marketing communications. This is due to a change to the rules which govern how we can communicate with you and new regulations on personal data (the General Data Protection Regulation) coming into force in May 2018. Therefore, we are introducing a new approach that relies on you giving us consent about how we contact you. This means you will have the choice as to whether you want to receive these messages and be able to select how you want to receive them (email or post).
You can decide not to receive communications or change how we contact you at any time. If you wish to do so please contact us by emailing: info@huddersfieldchoral.com or by writing to Huddersfield Choral Society, Merchant Hse, 24 Cheapside, Wakefield WF1 2TF
We will never sell your personal data, and will only ever share it with organisations we work with where necessary and if its privacy and security are guaranteed.
2. ABOUT US
Your personal data (i.e. any information which identifies you, or which can be identified as relating to you personally) will be collected and used by the Huddersfield Choral Society (Registered Charity no. 1100851 & Company no. 04925029)
3. WHAT INFORMATION WE COLLECT
We collect data you provide to us. This includes information you give when joining or registering, placing an order or communicating with us. For example:
personal details (name, date of birth, email, address, telephone etc.) when you join as a Subscriber, Member, Partner, Sponsor, Patron or Friend.
financial information (payment information such as credit/debit card or direct debit details, and whether donations are gift-aided.
details of your interests and preferences (such as concerts or recordings you enjoy).
If you purchase membership as a gift for someone, join as a family your relationship to that person will be recorded.
Information created by your involvement with HCS:
Your activities and involvement with HCS will result in personal data being created. This could include details of how you’ve supported us by volunteering or being involved with our activities.
If you decide to donate to us, then we will keep records of when and how much you gave to a particular cause.
Information we generate:
We conduct research and analysis on the information we hold, which can in turn generate personal data. For example, by analysing your interests and involvement with HCS, we may be able to build a profile which helps us decide which of our events or concerts are likely to interest you.
Information from third parties:
We sometimes receive personal data about individuals from third parties. For example, if we are partnering with another organisation (e.g. you provide your information to another Society we’re collaborating with on a project).
We may collect information from social media where you have given us permission to do so, or if you post on one of our social media pages.
Occasionally, we may collect information about certain supporters (e.g. particularly well known or influential people) from public sources. This could include public databases (such as Companies House), news or other media. We don’t do this to everyone, and it is the exception not the rule.
Sensitive personal data:
We do not collect or store sensitive personal data (such as information relating to health, beliefs or political affiliation) about supporters and members.
Accidents or incidents:
If an accident or incident occurs at one of our events or to one of our staff (including volunteers) then we’ll keep a record of this.
Volunteer:
If you are a volunteer (whether for specifically HCS, or if you are helping us for other reasons - for example you work for another organisation which is running an event with us) then we may collect extra information about you (e.g. references, criminal records checks, details of emergency contacts, medical conditions etc.). This information will be retained for legal reasons, to protect us (including in the event of an insurance or legal claim) and for safeguarding purposes.
4. HOW WE USE INFORMATION
We only ever use your personal data with your consent, or where it is necessary in order to:
enter into, or perform, a contract with you;
comply with a legal duty;
protect your vital interests;
for our own (or a third party’s) lawful interests, provided your rights don’t override the these.
In any event, we will only use your information for the purpose or purposes it was collected for or for closely related purposes.
b: Marketing:
We use personal data to communicate with people, to promote the HCS and to help with fundraising. This includes keeping you up to date with our news, updates, campaigns and fundraising information.
c: Administration:
We use personal data for administrative purposes. This includes:
receiving donations (e.g. direct debits or gift-aid instructions);
maintaining databases of our Subscribers, Members, Patrons, Partners, Sponsors and Friends;
performing our obligations under membership contracts;
fulfilling orders for goods or services (whether placed online, over the phone or in person);
helping us respect your choices and preferences (e.g. if you ask not to receive marketing material, we’ll keep a record of this).
d: Internal research and analysis:
We carry out research and analysis on our Subscribers, Members, Patrons, Partners, Sponsors and Friends to determine the success of campaigns, better understand behaviour and responses and identify patterns and trends. This helps inform our approach towards campaigning and make HCS a stronger and more effective organisation. Understanding our supporters, their interests and what they care about also helps us provide a better experience (e.g. through more relevant communications).
e: Supporter research and profiling:
We evaluate, categorise and profile personal data in order to tailor materials, services and communications better. (including targeted advertising) This prevents unwanted material from filling up your inbox. This also helps us understand our supporters and improve our organisation.
4. DISCLOSING AND SHARING DATA
We will never sell your personal data. If you have opted-in to marketing, we may contact you with information about our partners, or third party products and services, but these communications will always come from HCS and are usually incorporated into our own marketing materials.
We may share personal data with subcontractors or suppliers who provide us with services. For example, if you order something from the HCS website, your name and address will be shared with the delivery company. However, these activities will be carried out under a contract which imposes strict requirements on our supplier to keep your information confidential and secure.
Occasionally, where we partner with other organisations, we may also share information with them (for example, if you register to attend an event being jointly organised by us and another Society). We’ll only share information when necessary and we’ll make sure to notify you first.
5. MARKETING
From 16 March 2018, HCS will ask its supporters to “opt-in” for all communications. This includes all our marketing communications (the term marketing is broadly defined and, for instance, covers information about concerts, recordings and events by HCS).
This means you’ll have the choice as to whether you want to receive these messages and be able to select how you want to receive them (post or email).
You can decide not to receive communications or change how we contact you at any time. If you wish to do so please contact us at: info@huddersfieldchoral.com
What does ‘marketing’ mean?
Marketing does not just mean offering things for sale, but also includes news and information about:
our performances and recording work;
membership benefits;
volunteering opportunities and how you can help or get involved;
appeals and fundraising (including donations and raffles etc.);
our events and activities;
products and services (our own, and those of third parties which may interest you);
leaving a legacy;
taking part in projects;
When you receive a communication, we may collect information about your response as this may affect how we communicate with you in future.
Fundraising:
As a charity, we rely on donations and support from others to continue our work. From time to time, we will contact members and supporters with fundraising material and communications. This might be about the forthcoming season, a competition we’re running, or other fundraising activities.
As with other marketing communications, we’ll only contact you specifically about fundraising if you’ve "opted in" to receiving marketing from us (and you can, of course, unsubscribe at any time).
6. HOW WE PROTECT DATA
We employ a variety of physical and technical measures to keep your data safe and to prevent unauthorised access to or use or disclosure of your personal information.
Electronic data and databases are stored on secure computer systems, and we control who has access to information (using both physical and electronic means). Our staff receive data protection training and we have a set of detailed data protection procedures which personnel are required to follow when handling personal data.
7. STORAGE
Where we store information
The HCS’s operations are based in the UK and we store our data within the European Union. Some organisations which provide services to us may transfer personal data outside of the EEA, but we will only allow them to do this if your data is adequately protected.
How long we store information:
We will only use and store information for so long as it is required for the purposes it was collected for. If you ask us not to send you marketing emails, we will stop storing your emails for marketing purposes (though we’ll keep a record of your preference not to be emailed).
We continually review what information we hold and delete what is no longer required. We never store payment card information.
8. KEEPING YOU IN CONTROL
We want to ensure you remain in control of your personal data. Part of this is making sure you understand your legal rights, which are as follows:
the right to confirmation as to whether or not we have your personal data and, if we do, to obtain a copy of the personal information we hold (this is known as subject access request);
the right to have your data erased (though this will not apply where it is necessary for us to continue to use the data for a lawful reason);
the right to have inaccurate data rectified;
the right to object to your data being used for marketing or profiling;
Please keep in mind that there are exceptions to the rights above and, though we will always try to respond to your satisfaction, there may be situations where we are unable to do so.
If you would like further information on your rights or wish to exercise them, please email: info@huddersfieldchoral.com
Complaints:
You can complain to the HCS directly by contacting us using the details set out above.
If you are not happy with our response, or you believe that your data protection or privacy rights have been infringed, you can complain to the UK Information Commissioner’s Office which regulates and enforces data protection law in the UK. Details of how to do this can be found at www.ico.org.uk
9. COOKIES AND LINKS TO OTHER SITES
Links to other sites
Our website contains hyperlinks to other websites. We are not responsible for the content or functionality of any of those external websites (but please let us know if a link is not working by using the 'Contact us' page).
When purchasing goods or services from any of the businesses that our site links to, you will be entering into a contract with them (agreeing to their terms and conditions) and not with HCS.
10. CHANGES TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY
We’ll amend this Privacy Policy from time to time to ensure it remains up-to-date and accurately reflects how and why we use your personal data. The current version of our Privacy Policy will always be posted on our website.
This Privacy Policy was last updated on 18/07/18
Browse
Music Professionals
About
Choir
Outreach
Gallery
FAQ
Jeremy Garside,
General Secretary,Revenue Chambers,St Peter’s Street, Huddersfield,West Yorkshire,HD1 1DL
